Thomas Glaser

58 Forest Road, Windsor, SL4 4HU

07480 503 505 - thomas@tkglaser.net

Profile

I have 14 years commercial experience in the IT services and software delivery industry. During this time I mainly fulfilled the roles of a Senior Software Engineer and Technical Team Lead. Prior to this I have successfully graduated as a Master of Computer Science at the Technical University of Ilmenau, Germany.

I have an excellent track record from a technical point of view and received consistently positive feedback about my pro-active approach, outstanding communication skills and team work.

In addition to interesting technical tasks, a large part of my job satisfaction is coming from solving real-life customer needs and I enjoy ongoing interaction with stakeholders as only this ensures the best outcome possible.

Key skills: Web Development on the Microsoft stack, MS SQL + ASP + Angular.

Skills

Programming Languages	
C#	12 Years
C++	5 Years
JavaScript	4 Years
Markup Languages	
X/HTML	10 Years
XML	10 Years
XSLT	3 Years
IDE	
VS 6 – VS 2017	17 Years
Visual Studio Code	2 Years
Data Storage and Management	
MS SQL Server 2008 – 2016	4 Years
Jenkins	1 Year
Web Servers	
IIS 5 – 8	9 Years
MS Azure	4 Years
Architecture, Design Patterns	
Distributed Systems	N-Tier
OOP, OOD	MVC
MVVM	Unit of work
Singleton	Responsive Web
Code First	Database First

Leadership		
Technical Team Lead	4 Years	
IT Director	1.5 Years	
Web Technologies		
.NET Core	1.5 Years	
WebForms	4 Years	
ASP MVC 2 – 5, Razor	3.5 Years	
WebAPI 1 – 2	1 Year	
CSS	10 Years	
Angular (2+)	3 Years	
Desktop/Mobile Technologies		
Winforms	4 Years	
Source Control, Bug Tracking		
Subversion	8 Years	
Git	4.5 Years	
TFS	1.5 Years	
.Net Frameworks		
1.1 - 4.7	9 Years	
Frameworks, Extensions & ORM		
LINQ	3 Years	
Entity Framework 3 – 6	3 Years	

Experience

Invenias - Senior Web Developer (contract)

October 2018 - Current

Re-implementation of Web-Based CMS in Angular 7.

Tools/Languages: Angular (v7), RxJS (Reactive extensions for JS), @ngrx/store (State manager), C#, Visual Studio 2017, Visual Studio Code.

This client was struggling with performance issues, maintainability and stability. I've taken the following steps to move them forward:

- Start to re-implement the application using several new concepts in a side-by-side way, so
 the improvements can be seen immediately. It is not just a like-for-like, many new features
 were implemented along the way.
- Introduce @ngrx/store for client-side state management and caching.
- Migrate from Angular 4 to Angular 7 to take advantage of out-of-the-box performance improvements.
- Move them to the new Angular CLI build system. This took dev builds from 8 minutes down to 2.
- Set up code linting to highlight anti-patterns and use of deprecated features.
- Educate the team on all the new concepts so that they can to move forward.

Fisery - Senior Web Developer (contract)

October 2017 - October 2018

Re-implementation of Risk Assessment Software in Angular 5.

Tools/Languages: **C#**, **WebAPI**, **Angular** (v5), **RxJS** (Reactive extensions for JS), **@ngrx/store** (State manager), **Visual Studio 2015**, **Visual Studio Code**, **MS SQL Server**.

The old version of the FCRM risk assessment software was implemented in Silverlight and had to be re-implemented in Angular. This included writing a REST API wrapper for the legacy server-side logic using WebAPI. The client-side application was then created from scratch using Angular.

I did some work on the server-side back-end, but I mainly focused on the client-side Angular application and ended up writing about 80% of the app on my own. There was a heavy focus on observability (data changes in one part of the UI affecting other parts), so we heavily used the @ngrx/store, @ngrx/entities and @ngrx/effects packages to manage and observe client-side state changes.

Knight Frank - Senior Web Developer

July 2015 – September 2017

Extending and updating Knight Frank's web presence.

Tools/Languages: C#, ASP MVC, .NET Core 1.1, AngularJS (1.x) Angular (2+), jQuery, ASP WebApi, WebForms, Visual Studio 2015, MS SQL Server

I have rewritten Knight Frank's property search application from scratch. I have also done multiple smaller projects for Knight Frank, including:

- A UK stamp duty calculator (JavaScript/jQuery) http://www.knightfrank.co.uk/stamp-duty-calculator
- A new office and people search plugin (AngularJS, WebAPI)

Couchbase Inc. - Software Trainer (contract)

July 2015 - Oct 2016

I have trained some of Couchbase's customers in the use of the Couchbase C SDK (libcouchbase).

Magnitude Internet GmbH – IT Director, Software Engineer

Oct 2014 - Oct 2018

Technical director of a German start-up company and responsible for architecture and development.

Tools/Languages: C#, ASP.NET MVC 5, ASP Web API 2, AngularJS, MS Azure

HM Informatik AG – Senior Software Engineer (contract)

Mar 2014 – June 2015

I have written multiple plugins for a Flight Control Simulation software (FCS).

Tools/Languages: C++, Boost, CMake, QT 4.8, Visual Studio 2010, Bazaar.

Momentum Coach Hire Ltd – IT Director, Senior Software Engineer, Consultant

Sep 2011 – Mar 2014

I have been working for Momentum Coach Hire, a small ambitious company in the Coach Hire and Event Organisation business. There, I have created a variety of new web sites and improved existing ones. I've moved some of the existing ones to Azure, all the new ones were hosted on Azure from the start. I have also been promoted to IT Director and was responsible for the migration of the entire company (50 employees) onto Microsoft Office 365.

Tools/Languages: C#, ASP.NET MVC 3-4, Google Maps API, MS Azure

Symantec UK Ltd – Senior Software Engineer

Feb 2010 – Sep 2011

I have worked as a Senior Software Engineer for Symantec UK Ltd in the Research and Development team for Symantec Enterprise Vault, an email archiving solution written in C# and C++. In my time there I have performed the following tasks:

- Completed or am working on a number of small to medium projects including new features and architectural enhancements to improve resilience.
- For these projects, I have created the functional specification and software design documents and have implemented them on my own or as part of a team.
- Main tools/skills used:
 - OOA, OOD, Database Design, UML
 - MS Visual Studio 2008, C#, C++, XSLT, MS SQL Server 2008

- Fixed many defects in different code streams as part of learning the project architecture
- Received outstanding performance reviews for pro-actively driving architectural improvements and my excellent communication and team work

Ingres Europe Ltd – Senior Software Engineer

Mar 2004 – Feb 2010

With Ingres I worked as a permanently employed Consultant. I was involved in various customer projects as a developer and architect.

Education

Technical University of Ilmenau

- Diplom Informatiker (Dipl. Inf.) Equivalent to 2:1 Master in Computer Science
- Primary Subject: Computer Science "Good" (2.2)
- Secondary Subject: Mathematics "Good" (1.7)
- Diploma Thesis: "Toolbox with Interactors for Geometric Modelling in Virtual Reality" "Good" (2.3)
- Various extracurricular Activities like Manager of a Student Club.

Training received

Time	Content
Jan 2011	Effective C++
Jul 2010	Lotus Domino Administration Boot camp
Feb 2008	Application Development in OpenROAD
Jan 2008	Migrating ABF to OpenROAD
Dec 2007	Jaspersoft, iReport, JasperServer
Oct 2007	Visual Studio 2008, .NET 3.5
Jun 2005	V-Model XT
May 2005	QM System ISO 9001
Aug 2004	MS Project Server
Jul 2004	Train the Trainer
Apr 2004	QM System ISO 9001

Interests

- Open Source Community, Linux
- Playing Guitar
- Racquet Sports

References

Excellent references available on request.